# Sanjay Shrestha

Full-stack Designer, HFI CUA™



http://sanjayshrestha.com
https://behance.net/shresthasans
https://dribbble.com/shresthasans
https://linkedin.com/in/shresthasans
http://github.com/shresthasans
http://jsfiddle.net/user/shresthasans
http://codepen.io/shresthasans

dziner.sanjay@gmail.com sanzaysan (skype) +9779849645811

#### **About Me**

Full-stack designer, Certified Usability Analyst (CUA<sup>™</sup>) by HFI and a Nepalese, have around ten (10) years of experience in UX/UI Design and UI Development, been with start-ups to large tech companies, created huge impact on leading product definition and development, improving user-experience in B2B and B2C software products.

#### **Skills**

**Specialties** UX research and analysis, Requirement analysis, Competitive analysis, IA, IxD,

Prototyping, Stakeholder Interview, User-centric clean & modern visual design,

Web accessibility, Usability testing, A/B Testing, Heuristic Analysis, UI

Development, SEO, powerpoint/keynote presentation

**Data Analysis** FullStory, Hotjar, VWO, Google Analytics

PM Tools Axosoft, Basecamp, Asana, Jira

**Graphics Software** Sketch, Figma, Photoshop, Illustrator, Balsamiq, Axure RP, InVision, Moqups

Languages (X)HTML 4/5, CSS2/3, Sass/SCSS, LESS, JavaScript, Jade, Haml

FED Frameworks Material Design, Bootstrap, Foundation, jQuery, jQueryUI, jQuery Mobile

**Dev Tools** Grunt, Gulp, Webpack, YEOMAN, Bower

VCS Git, SVN, TFS

Methodologies Atomic Design, OOCSS, SMACSS, BEM, DRY, KISS

## **Selected Projects**

#### UX (Research & Analysis)

- Avira Antivirus | Wireframe
- Avanade | Wireframe
- Invoice App
- Smart Class Schedule
- HR Dashboard
- Nepal PMO | Wireframe
- Bifrost
- Zero Meetings | Wireframe

#### Mobile App/Websites projects

- What the Score Sports App
- Get a Cab Cab Booking App
- Futnotes Sports App

#### Wireframes

- Pagevamp Inc (Frontend and Backend)
- Zero Meeting Meeting web app

#### UI Design & Development projects

- Flash Pack
- Pagevamp Inc
- Singapore Government Provident Fund
- Mage Security Council
- Dashboard UI
- Website Theme Design

#### Logo Design

- Innova Consulting
- Magesec.org
- Mojo Stratus
- Vintuna Creatives

#### Giveaway

- MM18NYC Swag Bag
- MM18NYC T-shirt

#### **Flyers**

- Commerce Hero Product Marketing
- Magento Security Council Marketing
- MageMojo Product Marketing
- Nomad Mage Website Marketing

#### **Event Badge Design**

Meet Magento 2017 NYC

#### Ads Design

- Google Ads for Magemojo
- Facebook Ads for Magemojo

#### Poster Design (Typographic)

Wall stickers

#### Visiting Card Design

- Evolve fashion house
- Sanjay Shrestha Freelancer

## **Work History**

#### June 2016 - till date (Freelance)

## **UX Architect / UI Developer**

MageMojo LLC., Pittsburgh, United States (https://magemojo.com)

#### Roles and Responsibilities:-

- Brainstorm, research, wireframe, design and refine user experiences
- Work closely with product managers and the engineering team to create simple, easy-to-use products
- Provide multiple types of deliverables, including wireframes, workflow diagrams, interactive demos, and final mockups
- Create, improve and extend designs for MageMojo's Products
- Maintaining UX and UI end of MageMojo's Website and Knowledge Base
- Website Maintenance and Events branding
- Graphics Design
- Designing and Development of Responsive Email Templates for Campaigns.
- Front-end Development

#### Feb 2018 - Oct 2018 (Full time)

### **Product Manager & UX Lead**

WhiteHat Engineering Inc (https://whitehatengineering.com)

#### Roles and Responsibilities:-

- Project Management with AGILE (Scrum)
- Ensuring the ongoing growth and motivation of the business by creating concepts and ideas for increasing revenue
- Active participation in brainstorming sessions for client campaigns and Marketing Eye strategies
- Playing a key role in the design lifecycle, from brief through to design and release/implementation
- Ensuring all designs work across all browsers and on all devices
- Developing specifications for designs to determine their feasibility.
- Usability Testing and identify any technical problems
- Social networks design and development
- Online marketing as required
- Assist in the development of marketing campaigns as required

### <u> Jan 2017 - Jan 2018 (Full time)</u>

#### **UX Architect**

Pagevamp Inc., Kathmandu, Nepal (https://pagevamp.com)

#### Roles and Responsibilities:-

- UX Research and Analysis
- User/Stakeholder interviews
- Documentation
- Wireframing and Prototyping
- Visual Design
- Data Analysis
- A/B Testing
- Front-end development using HTML, CSS and JavaScript/jQuery.

#### June 2014 - July 2016 (Full time)

## UX Consultant - UX/UI Development

Microsoft R&D Pvt. Ltd., Hyderabad, India (http://www.microsoft.com)

#### Roles and Responsibilities:-

- Actively engaging in UX/UI analysis and Usability.
- Front-end Development with HTML(5), CSS(3) and JavaScript/JQuery.
- XAML App development
- Working on ASP.NET MVC Platform.
- Developing prototypes based on Bootstrap framework.
- Working with LESS/SASS CSS preprocessor.
- Working with Grunt and its counterpart.

#### April 2013 - May 2014 (Full time)

#### Sr. Front-end Developer

TQID (Top Quality Internet Development), KTM, Nepal (http://www.tqid.com)

#### **Key Accomplishment:-**

- Handled a dev team and was the in-touch person for any front-end related issues.
- Started the UX approach for Web and Software development.
- Started using Grunt, SASS and LESS CSS for the front-end development project.
- Developing prototypes based on Bootstrap framework.
- JQuery Mobile app development.

#### June 2012 - March 2013 (Full time)

## **UX/UI** Designer cum Front-End Developer

Neudesic Technologies, Bangalore, India (http://www.neudesic.com)

#### **Key Accomplishment: -**

- Worked on a large project in .net platform using Bootstrap Framework and LESS CSS.
- Gained experience in the AGILE development process with a distributed team across the globe.
- Gained experience in various aspects of User Experience Fundamentals Requirement Analysis, User
- Profiling/Grouping, Personas, Task Analysis, Wireframes, Prototyping, Usability Testing

#### Aug 2011 - May 2012 (Full time)

## **UI Designer/Front-End Developer**

Software And Mine Pvt. Ltd., KTM, Nepal (http://www.andmine.com)

#### **Key Accomplishment:-**

- Gained experience with RWD (Responsive Web Design).
- Worked on several Responsive websites using Twitter Bootstrap and coding from scratch with full browser compatibility.
- Gained experience in Bigcommerce template customization.
- Started a new process to design Mobile Sites/Apps based on ¡Query Mobile.
- Known as a kick-ass UI designer and CSS Ninja.

#### July 2010 - Aug 2011 (Full time)

## **UI Designer/Front-End Developer**

Crossover Web Solution, KTM, Nepal (http://www.crossovernepal.com)

#### **Key Accomplishment:-**

- Gained experience in HTML5/CSS3 with pixel perfect coding.
- Gained experience in Wordpress template customization.
- Worked on lots of EDM projects.
- Designed UIs for several popular US, AU and UK brands.
- Gained experience on customizing JQuery Plugins.

## **Education**

2009 - 2012	Bachelor in Humanities – BA (English Literature and Social Science) Tribhuvan University (TU), Kathmandu, Nepal
2006 - 2008	10 + 2 (A level equivalent - English Literature and Social Science) Higher Secondary Education Board (HSEB), Kathmandu, Nepal

## Languages

Excellent in English, Fluent in Hindi, Nepali (Native), Newari (Mother Tongue)